DEBRA WILKIE

linkedin.com/in/debra-wilkie

Profile

Experienced leader of cross-functional teams utilizing Agile/Scrum skills and analytical abilities to plan, build and launch products. Excellent problem solver who enjoys learning, exploring, and diving-in to a project and looks forward to applying strategic planning skills and leadership abilities to solving the next challenge.

Highlights

- Strategic Planning
- Communication/Presentations
- Agile/Scrum Methodologies
- Test-Driven Development
- User Story Creation
- Functional Backend and UI Testing
- Analytical Skills
- Ingestion and User Logging
- Product Documentation

Professional Experience

GE / Belcan | Wilmington, NC Project Manager

July 2018 - Present

- Developing, testing and implementing a new software application for an American Fortune 100 energy company in collaboration with GE
- Communicating with clients to discuss design needs and organize project requirements according to a value based level of priorities
- Building credibility, establishing rapport and maintaining a high degree of client satisfaction by timely responding to ongoing software support and training
- Leading and collaborating with development team using Agile methods to discuss and design software applications including daily standup meetings, design sessions, user story creation via CA Rally
- Trouble shooting and debugging skills including creating functional backend and UI tests to address potential software defects
- Drafting and delivering over 20+ pages of product documentation in Confluence with varied content for use with new team members, client explanations of value, technical coding dictionaries, and product marketing
- Collaborating with data scientists and other project managers to implement new reporting structures via Excel and Tableau for stakeholder meetings increasing the efficiency in reporting and data reliability

Bell Shoals Baptist Church | Brandon, FL Website Redesign Project Manager and Database Administrator

January 2016 – June 2017

- Developed and deployed updated Bell Shoals Academy website
 - o Discussed with client (Headmaster) the design needs
 - Conducted market research to assess current requirements and trends
 - Created project timeline to meet objectives
 - Vetted and hired companies to integrate required technologies seamlessly into overall project
 - o Conducted product testing with select feedback group (teachers, parents) and implemented changes
 - Deployed website utilizing SEO
- Improved processes for data retrieval and analysis and resolved problems and after switch from Shelby to Ministry Platform database system for a 5-campus church
- Improved database queries for creation of new classes as well as registration for continuing classes with 300+ students
- Created SQL database notifications to email appropriate contact of new registrations and required tasks
- Created Excel presentation from SQL queries to analyze the potential for a new church campus site

DEBRA WILKIE

linkedin.com/in/debra-wilkie

- Coded new HTML website/database skin to incorporate online payment portal and database account management for church events including mission trip purchase histories
- Integrated new website platforms including Church Online platform for live web streaming and RightNow Media

Parris Island Officer Spouses Club | Parris Island, SC Philanthropy Officer and Website Manager

May 2013 – May 2015

- Coordinated 3 volunteer projects, collaborated with various agencies for distribution and contacted businesses for auction donations
- Created advertisements for the auction on websites and newspapers, as well as distributing flyers
- Organization of guest registration, auction check out, and overall guest experience to ensure successful event
- Ensuring donor retention by writing personal notes of thanks and updating donation logs
- Web Manager; researched, designed, modified and maintained website
- Highly self-motivated with the ability to quickly learn and utilize innovative technologies

Technical College of the Lowcountry | Beaufort, SC Adjunct Professor

May 2012 - Present

- Independently created and organized courses utilizing Blackboard's online learning management system
- Integrated learning objectives with the instructional materials utilizing multiple technologies to enhance learner interaction and usability
- Redesigned and taught a Music Appreciation Course in a 16 week on campus format as well a 10, 8, and 7 week online course
- Highly developed verbal skills with the ability to develop written directives and present material through PowerPoints, lectures and active discussions
- Resolved conflicts with students regarding grade disputes utilizing the academic policies

University of Tampa | Tampa, FL Adjunct Professor of Voice

August 2008 – May 2011

- Ensured that learning objectives and course requirements were understood and developed supplemental resources to enhance knowledge
- Identified a possible curriculum addition and created and presented recommendations to department chair
- Collaborated with colleague to refine and create the course curriculum
- Implemented recommended changes in a timely fashion which resulted in 2 new classes added to the schedule

Education

Computer Science BS, Post-Baccalaureate

Oregon State University | eCampus

Bachelor of Music & Master of Music

Indiana University | Bloomington, IN

Skills

- Computer Skills: MS Office (Excel), Windows and Apple OS
- Computer Programming Skills: HTML, Node.js, PHP, Python, SQL
- Computer Technologies: Android Studio, GitHub, Linux, Tableau

DEBRA WILKIE

linkedin.com/in/debra-wilkie

• Learning Management Systems: Blackboard, Canvas, Edsby, Google Classroom

Volunteer Highlights

- Topsail High School; School Improvement Team (Parent Representative)
- Scotts Hill Baptist Church; Production Team Computer Graphics/Lyrics (Volunteer)
- Habitat for Humanity (Volunteer)